

PRADEEP MATHEW

DevOps Automation Engineer

PROFILE

A seasoned IT professional based in Melbourne, Australia, with diverse experience in banking, consulting, insurance, retail, and entertainment industries in DevOps and Cloud Platform engineering.

I bring over 5 years of robust experience in cloud engineering and automation, primarily focusing on AWS and Azure-based workloads.

CONTACT

Mobile:

+61 0415 250 136

WEBSITE:

https://pradeepmathewdev.com/

FMAII.

pradeepishere2005@gmail.com

SKILLS

Agile Methodologies Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD)

GII

Kubernetes

Bash

Buildkite

Codepipeline

SQL

Docker Products

Jenkins

Azure DevOps

Ansible

DevSecOps

Microservices

Microsoft Azure

Python

Linux

Terraform

ArgoCD

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Robotic Process Automation (RPA)

Release Management

Jira & Confluence

WORK RIGHTS

Australian Citizen

EDUCATION

MS University

2000 - 2004

Bachelor of Engineering - Major-Computer Science

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Solution Architect Associate
- AWS Cloud Practitioner
- GitOps Fundamentals
- HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate
- Azure DevOps Engineer Expert
- Azure Administrator
- Azure Fundamentals
- ITIL 3&4 Foundation

WORK EXPERIENCE

Coles Senior DevOps Consultant February 2024–Current

- Part of Technology Innovation team and is dedicated to reinventing the shopping experience for customers and building the next generation of digital retailing.
- Worked on deploying the 'Intelligent Edge Backbone' (IEB) solution computer vision micro services application as it scales to hundreds of stores across Australia.
- Led the plan, build, test and deployment on Kubernetes cluster-RKE, deploy micro services and applications, and monitor and troubleshoot issues.
- Specialized in areas like Azure DevOps, Kubernetes, YAML, Kustomize, and more. Additionally, play a crucial role in maintaining cloud resources, monitoring dashboards, and supporting edge devices in the digital infrastructure landscape

Tabcorp DevOps Automation Engineer-CI/CD

December 2021-February 2024

- Developed automation code for building CI/CD pipelines, Kubernetes clusters, and cloud infrastructure, embracing Agile methodologies.
- Led the deployment and management of a Java based real time transaction monitoring microservices application hosted on Kubernetes for Spring Racing Carnival.
- Automated HR recruitment workflow via UiPath Automation Suite.
- Integrated and managed SonarQube, Docker images, and GitHub for version control.
- Integrated and managed APM applications (New Relic, Splunk) for robust monitoring.
- Contributed to Java, Golang, and Python development, adept at debugging code-level issues.
- Actively participated in BAU application enhancements.
- Applied Terraform & CloudFormation for infrastructure provisioning.
- Managed Release and change for Automation & Engineering BU.
- Conducted thorough code reviews and sought DevSecOps opportunities for cost optimization in infrastructure and application code bases using Cloudconformity, Crowdstrike, Aqua, Snyk, and Billing dashboards.

Coles Release Operations Environment Analyst

June 2018-November 2021

- Led Build and Deployment Insights data warehousing projects on Snowflake, PowerBI, Datafactory, ETL and Oracle.
- Collaborate with various projects for weekly twice code progression to production environments.
- Built and managed cloud resources on Azure Datafactory, Azure Pipelines, Azure Key vault, Azure AD, Storage and AKS.
- Developed automation scripts in Bash, Python, and PowerShell.
- Implemented CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins and Azure DevOps, integrating Snowflake and PowerBI components seamlessly.
- Administered change/release records in ITSM tool (ServiceNow) and coordinated cross-team collaboration.
- Led cloud migrations, enhanced release processes, and advocated for DevOps practices, optimizing on-premises and cloud operations.

IAG Environment Analyst

February 2014-May 2018

- Managed environment and code release deployments using build and automation tools.
- Set up lab environments for diverse projects, encompassing estimation, system design, development, and implementation.
- Led infrastructure and application upgrade projects, coordinating with vendors.
- SME of environment management team for Wesfarmers IAG Systems integration, Coles IAG systems integration, OpenText Capture systems and Adlib Application upgrade projects.
- Contributed to daily monitoring, maintenance, and patching of non-production server environments, and worked on cloud-based pipelines for document management solutions at IAG.

Capgemini Senior Consultant

September 2012-January 2014

- Effectively managed and resolved environmental support issues, addressing root causes and defects.
- Participated in regular, fast-track, and emergency releases, QA testing, business continuity testing, and vendor patch management.
- Collaborated closely with diverse teams, including testing, infrastructure, development, and release management.
- Served as the main point of contact for technical support issues related to servers, databases, debugging, and configurations within the Global Payments Applications team.
- Accomplished projects, including IBM Master Data Management implementation, Windows system upgrades, and a hardware refresh project for the Voucher Image 'Storage' System.

ANZ Technical Analyst

May 2006-August 2012

Worked as Test Environment management analyst across the major ANZ projects.

- Global Information Security team offshore setup and coordination
- Global payments systems integration with PRIME regulatory systems
- Microsoft Reporting Services Application Upgrade Program
- CA Clarity v8 Application Upgrade/ PAYPLUS-FX online integration Program/ Australia Post Forward Clearing Project
- Data Integrator Program (Royal Bank of Singapore)